Gabriel Eduardo Palhares

E-mail: gabrielpalharesdev@gmail.com | Phone: +55 31 99543-8335

Github: https://github.com/minortypo/ | LinkedIn: https://github.com/minortypo/

Location: Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

Driver's License: Category B (cars)

About/Objective

I am a software development professional and computer science enthusiast. I am currently transitioning careers and seeking internship, trainee, and/or junior software developer positions.

Skills

I have proficiency in JavaScript and TypeScript, and knowledge in React.js, Next.js, Node.js, and Nest.js. I have experience with relational and non-relational databases such as PostgreSQL and MongoDB. I use Jest and Vitest as software testing tools. I possess strong foundations in the software development lifecycle (SDLC), algorithms and data structures, functional programming, HTML5, and CSS3. Additionally, I have advanced knowledge of Microsoft Excel.

Education

- Bachelor of Law (2019 2023), Faculdade Asa, Brumadinho/MG, Brazil.
- Associate Degree in Systems Analysis and Development (2022 2024), PUC Minas, Belo Horizonte/MG, Brazil.
- University Extension in Modern Software Engineering (2024 2024), UFMG Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte/MG, Brazil.

Professional Experience

Full-Stack Software Developer – Career Transition/Freelance • (January 2024 – Present).

Responsibilities: Development of software and web systems, freelance projects, study, and personal projects. Check my Portfolio.

Judicial Assistant – Court of Justice of Minas Gerais (TJMG) • (September 2022 – December 2023).

Responsibilities: Processing judicial cases through the Electronic Judicial Process system (PJe), performing procedural acts related to Family, Juvenile, Civil, and Criminal courts.

Administrative Manager - R&R Transportes • (August 2020 - September 2022).

Responsibilities: Administrative, financial, and organizational management of the company. Data control using spreadsheets and analysis in Excel, as well as data management and visualization with Power BI.

Languages

Advanced English (C1) – Native Portuguese – Basic Spanish (A1)

Courses

Harvard – CS50: Introduction to Computer Science.

USP University of São Paulo – Startup Creation: How to Develop Innovative Businesses.

Alura – Beginner in Programming (Logic, Architecture, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Git, and Github).

Rocketseat – Fullstack JavaScript (Typescript, React.js, Next.js, Node.js, and Nest.js).